Mohammed W. Ghabyen

Canakkale, Turkey • +90 (535) 634-1886

mohammedghabyen@gmail.com • MyWebsite • GitHub • LinkedIn

Summary

React Native developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science and 4+ years of experience at Silicon Valley and top MENA region companies. Achieved a 35% increase in code delivery, while contributing to open-source projects. Seeking to leverage proven leadership and expertise with my extensive experience and ability to lead successful projects.

Work Experience

React Native Developer Dec 2021–Present

Freelancer

- I have leveraged the power of React Native and native tools to successfully develop over 5 robust mobile apps.
- Delivered software 100% on time, meeting service-level objectives after testing, coding, and reviewing.
- Successfully developed a 3D body tracking app while working remotely at Zayn Innovations in Silicon Valley, CA.
- Integrated mobile applications with backend services (JSON, HTTP, REST, API, SQL, etc).

Mobile Application Developer

Apr 2021-Nov 2021

Fam Holding, UAE

- Boosted client's revenue by integrating ads platforms and supporting apps with 5k active users.
- Performed unit, system, and integration testing, and participated in capacity/performance testing.
- Optimized device software efficiency by 10% and improved system stability by 30%.

React Native Developer Sep 2019–Feb 2021

FUDEX, Saudi Arabia

- I have successfully published 3 high-quality mobile apps on both Google Play and the App Store.
- Award-winning developer of a standout application among 3000 contestants in the Tech Champions contest.
- Proficient in implementing optimization techniques such as caching, memory management, and asynchronous programming, resulting in highly performant and responsive applications.

React Native Developer

Oct 2018-Aug 2019

ICT Solutions Group, Palestine

- I enhanced the performance, reliability, and user experience through debugging and optimization techniques.
- Wrote clean, maintainable, and scalable code following industry best practices and coding standards.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to translate designs into high-quality responsive user interfaces.

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science

Sep 2010-Jun 2014

Al-Azhar University, Palestine

Skills

Expert ($\star \star \star \star \star$): JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React Native, React.js, Redux, Android, iOS, Firebase, Rest API. Advanced ($\star \star \star \star \star \star$): Scrum, Agile, CI-CD, DevOps, Postman, OOP, MVC, Atomic Design, Gradle, GraphQL, C#, Unity. Familiar ($\star \star \star \star \star \star$): Swift, Kotlin, Dart, Flutter, Figma, XD Design, Java, Bitbucket, C++.

Certifications

- Manara-Certified Software Engineer, Feb 2023.
- Educative: Algorithms Patterns and System Design, Dec 2022.
- IELTS Overall Band Score: Advanced, Dec 2021.